# J Hilger

# Flutter App Development Expert

#### J Hilger

650 Bloomfield Road Sebastopol, CA 95472

707-508-8389 jhilgerconsulting@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/jhilgerconsulting

#### **Objective**

As a programmer with 25 years of experience, I specialize in developing mobile applications with the same code base for Android and IOS to save money and unify the user experience with the focus of UI programming (Flutter/Dart).

I can help you and your company define an application vision, create a mock-up prototype and execute the implementation with your team or a team I can help hire and implement.

I am also available as a developer for your Flutter project.

# **Skills Highlights**

- Extensive experience in Google Dart and Flutter SDK with a focus on UX programming, C# / WPF and the .NET Framework, OOA/OOD, C, C++, XML, HTML5, Javascript, Typescript,
- Architected and implemented social media and car app for iOS/Android based on the Google Flutter / Dart Platform since early Alpha in 2016.
- Designed and implemented a Library of UI
   Components/Controls shared in the next generation of touch-enabled PC-based instruments using WPF and Dotnet.
- Wrote a data engine for Agilent Optical Spectrum analyzer.
- Was a representative in an international ISO (14230)
   Normative Task Force for serial communication standardization
- Specified, designed, and developed a reprogramming strategy for many car manufacturers.
- Designed and developed a new diagnostic car communication software for manufacturers worldwide.
- Strong record of software design and implementation for real-time and non-real-time systems.

#### **Experience**



#### Architect and Developer for ChkOBD - Self-Employed

MAY 2019 - PRESENT, SEBASTOPOL, CA

Developed car diagnostic apps for ChkOBD from design to implementation and released them on iOS and Android. The apps use many key components in the Flutter Framework like Bluetooth Classic and BLE, Firebase Database, Bloc Pattern, and Animations.

#### Please see the app here:

https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=\_I9zDRwLsyY&t=2s



## Architect for Look at my Baby - Self-Employed

MAY 2016 - MAY 2019

Developed a mobile social media application for an international company based in Australia. Led a team of three people and created the concept, prototype, mock-up, and application. Utilized Google Flutter Framework for multi-platform app development in early alpha.



## Senior User Interface Designer for Keysight Technologies

Jan 2000 - MAY 2016, SANTA ROSA, CA

Lead Architect of the User Interface Experience. Responsible for designing and implementing the User Interface of the Spectrum Analyzer and other touch-enabled Keysight instruments. Advocate for modern touch-driven user interfaces working with Keysight Human Factor Designers. Mentored and led other team members throughout the implementation cycle.



# Senior Software Engineer for Hewlett Packard

OCTOBER 1998 - JANUARY 2000, SANTA ROSA, CA

Implemented the data and math engine for the 86122C, the highest accuracy Multi-Wavelength Meter on the market. This instrument is used for measuring data channels in fiber optical cables.



#### **Software Developer**

AUGUST 1993 - SEPTEMBER 1998, SANTA ROSA, CA

Worked with ISO normative to design and prototype Diagnostic Protocols for the automotive industry. Responsible for the implementation and first customer introductions of the Keyword 2000 diagnostic (ISO 14230) protocol at VW, Mercedes, BMW, and many others.

**Education** 

**Bielefeld University / Master**'s Degree in Computer Science & Electrical Engineering

MONTH 1989 - MONTH 1993, LEMGO, GERMANY

Recommendations

For details please see my LinkedIn profile:

www.linkedin.com/in/jhilgerconsulting